MISAKI TIFFANY SHIMIZU

FRONT END DEVELOPER

PROJECTS

Daily Dad Jokes

GitHub Link Site Link

For this group project, I used React to build an interactive app where users can select a category of photos, input their own dad jokes, and display the results through a carousel. Through the use of Git, we were able to collaborate and successfully produce the request from the client.

Word Search

Site Link | GitHub Link

I created this app using the Merriam Webster API and exploring React and axios calls. The user is able to look up a word in the search bar and the API will pull the results and display a definition, pronunciation, and phonetics.

The Music Mood Generator

GitHub Link Site Link

To create this interactive app I utilized JavaScript, API, and SASS to allow users to select a mood and generate a song based on their selected mood. Users are able to view data pulled from the API that displays the album cover, song title, artist, and an audio clip of the song.

EXPERIENCE

Community Foundation of Mississauga Event Assistant

2020 - 2021

- Coordinated pre-and post-event planning with a team of 25 staff serving 150 customers.
- Juggled multiple projects and tasks to ensure high quality and timely
- Procured a team of 30 volunteers to help support two events.
- Created two event websites according to established standards and with high accuracy and efficiency.

Unialo

Sales Associate

2018 - 2020

- Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and advertising collateral.
- Delivered high level of assistance by locating products and checking store system for merchandise at other sites.
- Maintained organized, presentable merchandise to drive continuous sales.

SUMMARY

I am a front-end software developer that creates functional and responsive web designs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and API integrations. I have an educational background in Early Childhood Studies and have worked in the customer service / retail industry for 10+ years. My strong communication and problemsolving skills allow me to find new solutions and explore new ways to code.

CONTACT

(416)-524-6692



<u>tiffanyshimizu.com</u>



🖏 tshimizumisaki@gmail.com

EDUCATION

2021 - 2022

Juno College of Technology Web Development Bootcamp

2019 - 2020

Humber College

Graduate Certificate Event Management

2014 - 2019

Ryerson University

BA Early Childhood Studies

SKILL SET

- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Customer Service
- HTML5. CCS3
- JavaScript Fundamentals
- Responsive Designs